Finding Aid for Top Ladies of Distinction, Ann Arbor Chapter Records, 1982-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Top Ladies of Distinction, Ann Arbor Chapter Records 1982-1987
Top Ladies of Distinction. Ann Arbor Chapter.
0.3 linear feet
93809 Bk 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan chapter of an African American women's organization. Minutes, correspondence, and subject files; also minutes and newsletters of Detroit area district of the organization.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Flora Cherot (donor no. 8033 ) in May 1992.
The record group is open to research.
The Top Ladies Of Distinction, Ann Arbor Chapter (TLOD) is an African American women's service organization with programs directed toward youth, women, and senior citizens.. The Ann Arbor chapter, chartered in 1982, is part of the national TLOD organization. Flora Cherot, with the assistance of Dorothy Smith, First Vice President of the National Chapter of the Top Ladies of Distinctions, was the principal organizer of the Ann Arbor chapter. These women contacted Roberta Pickett who was the Area V Director, which included Detroit, to assist in the first meeting.
The purpose of the TLOD was to help alleviate the problems of young people, more specifically to sponsor a youth organization known as the TOP TEENS OF AMERICA, in order to provide opportunities for young people that would enhance their educational, social, spiritual, moral, cultural and economic development.
From 1982 until 1986, when the Ann Arbor chapter became inactive, the Top Ladies of Distinction had been involved in several projects ranging from Black College Month Observance to such alternative education programs as those offered by the Roberto Clemente Alternative Education Center in the Ann Arbor. The Ann Arbor chapter raised funding for local and national organizations and provided additional funds for continuing education through scholarships. The Top Ladies of Distinction also assisted other organizations. The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, and The National Council of Negro Women are two of the agencies receiving TLOD assistance and support.
The records of The Top Ladies Of Distinction, Ann Arbor Chapter comprise 0.3 linear feet of materials spanning the years 1982-1986. The collection is organized into three series: Ann Arbor Chapter, Area V (Detroit), and National Office. The collection documents the founding, development and operation of an important Black women organization. Included are such materials as minutes of meetings, correspondence, press releases and clippings, and other materials documenting the administration of the organization and its various outreach activities.
Subjects:
African American women.; African Americans--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
- Ann Arbor Chapter
  - Awards data sheets for TLOD recognition, undated (Box 1)
  - Constitution and bylaws (proposed), undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - Duties of Members, undated (Box 1)
  - Evaluation forms, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Financial, 1984-1987 (Box 1)
  - Local Service Projects and Annual Program Outlines, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - Membership materials, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea, undated (Box 1)
  - Press releases and clippings, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Program activities, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Service recommendations, undated (Box 1)
- Area V (Detroit)
  - Executive Board minutes and conference reports, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1981-1984 (Box 1)
- National Office
  - Hymn (Organizational Song) (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Program, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Top Teens of America, 1985-1986 (Box 1)